Ben Shaktman Papers
Ben Shaktman Papers
- Writings
  - Screenplays
    - "In My Father's House", 1972-1974
      - Research and notes (Box 54)
      - Story outlines, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - "Inside Out", undated (Box 54)
    - "The Nothing Child", 1973 (Box 54)
    - "Mother To My Mother", 1973 (Box 54)
      - Research (Box 54)
      - Story outlines (Box 54)
    - "My Kind Of Woman", 1974 (Box 54)
      - Drafts, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - First revision, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Notes (Box 54)
      - Scripts (Box 54)
    - "Tell Me All About Her", 1984
      - Correspondence (Box 55)
      - Drafts, 2 folders (Box 55)
      - Research and notes (Box 55)
      - Scripts (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous screenplay ideas and outlines, 1966; 1967,; undated (Box 55)
  - Television series and specials
    - "Place the Place", 1966 (Box 55)
    - "Revue", 1965-1966 (Box 55)
    - "Stunt Man", 1965-1966 (Box 55)
    - "The World Game", 1966 (Box 55)
  - Thesis "Negro In The New York Theater" Syracuse University, 1962
    - Actors and actresses (Box 55)
    - "The American Negro Theater" (Box 55)
    - Bibliography (Box 55)
    - Clippings and programs about individuals (Box 55)
    - Committee for the Employment of Negro Performers (Box 55)
    - Discrimination on the road (Box 55)
    - Eartha Kitt (Box 55)
    - Economics (Box 55)
    - Federal Theater (Box 55)
    - General notes and clippings (Box 55)
    - "Green Pastures" (Box 55)
    - History (Box 55)
    - Negro theater groups (Box 55)
    - Positive policy (Box 55)
    - Published material (Box 55)
    - Richard Wright (Box 55)
    - Sociology (Box 55)
    - Source material (Box 55)
    - Statistics (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 55)
- Memorabilia
  - Address books and calendars, 1970-2006 (Box 56)
  - Artwork
    - Print "Still Light" by David Freed, 18 x 22 (Map-case 110)
  - Clippings
    - Film and TV, 1998 (Box 56)
    - Paris, 2006 (Box 56)
    - Shaktman critical reviews, 1964-1974 (Box 56)
    - Theater, 1963-1964 (Box 56)
    - miscellaneous, 1965-2008 (Box 56)
  - Event programs
    - 1956-1968 (Box 57)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 58)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 59)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 60)
    - 1983-1987 (Box 61)
    - 1988-1992 (Box 62)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 63)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 64)
    - 2000-2009 (Box 65)
    - Undated (Box 66)
  - Phone messages (Box 67)
  - Photographs (Box 67)
  - Photographs, oversize
    - Black and white photograph of three women, oversize, framed, possibly theater prop? (Map-case 110)
    - Black and white photograph of black couple on bench (Map-case 110)
    - Black and white photo of montage of theater scenes, handwritten on back, "We will meet in the year we are sixty-two and you'll give notes as you used to do, VI Chaffon, 1982" (Map-case 110)
    - Photograph of clipping collage "Stahl Aktien Steigen", 50 x 64 (Map-case 110)
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 1)
  - Printed material (Box 67)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1996-2004 (Box 68)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1996-2004 (Tube 927)
  - Posters
    - 1941-1945 / PODVIG NARODA BESSMEPTEN ["The victor of the people is eternal"], Artist/mark: N. K. Vatolina; 66.5 x 96 (Map-case 110)
    - Amphitryon 38; Komodie von Jean Girardoux in den Kammerspielen, Deutsches Theater, 82 x 59 (Map-case 110)
    - Arnold Wesker's reading of his "Whatever Happened to Betty Lemon?", 1986 (Map-case 110)
    - Athol Fugard's The Blood Knot, Pittsburgh Public Theater; Allegheny Theater 4th Season, 1978-1979; Artist/mark: Gabriel Difiore Associates; 45.5 x 68.5 (Map-case 110)
    - Balyasnikov: A new play by Pittsburgh Public Theater; Aleksei Arbuzov, playwright, Pittsburgh Public Theater 3rd Season, 1977-1978; 46 x 73.5 (Map-case 110)
    - Benjamin Britten, Albert Hering oder Der Tugendpreis, Komische Oper, Artist/mark: Hei; 58.8 x 84 (Map-case 110)
    - Brecht, Leben Des Galilei, Berliner Ensemble am Schiffbauerdamm, 83.2 x 117.3 (Map-case 110)
    - Die Affaire Dreyfus, Artist/mark: Weyl 58; caption, "Liberte, Egalite, Fraternite"; 83.2 x 59 (Map-case 110)
    - Die Heilige Johanna, G. B. Shaw, Volksbuhne, 58.3 x 83.4 (Map-case 110)
    - Die Weber by Gerhart Hauptmann, Volksbuhne am Luxemburgplatz, Artist/mark: K 57; 58.5 x 83.2 (Map-case 110)
    - LA Chamber Music Festival, 1992; Artist/mark: Peter Alexander (signed) (Map-cas 110)
    - LIBERTAD!, 1967; Artist/mark: C.Y.63; secondary title in Cyrillic, transl. "Free people of Spain"; 55.5 x 70.5 (Map-case 110)
    - London Street Scene limited edition print (#175/25), signed and inscribed to Ben Shaktman, 1986; Artist/mark: John Allen (Map-case 110)
    - Macbeth von William Shakespeare, Volksbuhne, Artist/mark: Weyl 59; 81 x 57.6 (Map-case 110)
    - Neon Rose #15, 1967; 55.5 x 70.5 (Map-case 110)
    - Neuland Unterm Pflug/Scholochow, Deutsches Theater im Berliner Ensemble, Artist/mark: Reher; 58.5 x 83.2 (Map-case 110)
    - Oscar Wilde, "The Importance of Being Earnest," Pittsburgh Public Theatre 4th Season, 1978-1979; 45.5 x 68 (Map-case 110)
    - Pauken und Tromptene (Trumpets and Drums), Berliner Ensemble, Palace Theater, Artist/mark: Karl Appen 55; 83.8 x 118.2 (Map-case 110)
    - Picasso from the Musée Picasso, Paris, 1980; exhibit poster for exhibit at Walker Art Center, Minneapolis, Minnesota (Map-case 110)
    - Pittsburgh Public Theater 30th anniversary banner, VERY large, 2004
    - Scenic design sketch, black and white, Artist/mark: Ed Wittstein '74; 56.2 x 43.5 (Map-case 110)
    - Sommergaste; Maxim Gorki Shauspiel, Deutsches Theater, Artist/mark: Klemke 59; 83.8 x 58 (Map-case 110)
    - Supreme Court Planned Parenthood, 1992; Artist/mark: Robbie Conal (Map-case 110)
    - Tage die die Welt erschutterten, Volksbuhne 10, Artist/mark: Weyl 57; 58.5 x 83.6 (Map-case 110)
    - Venice Art Walk, 1990; Artist/mark: John Baldessari (signed) (Map-case 110)
    - Wallenstein Trilogie, Deutsches Theater, 80 x 59 (Map-case 110)
  - Postcards (Box 67)
  - Scrapbook: Syracuse University, 1962-1963 (Box 67)
  - Scheduling planners, 1982-1986 (Box 67)
  - Travel souvenirs
    - Bermuda, 2006 (Box 69)
    - Big Sur, California, 2007 (Box 69)
    - China, 2000 (Box 69)
    - Maine, 1994 (Box 69)
    - Napa Valley and Sonoma, California, 1995 (Box 69)
    - Sedona, Arizona, 1992 (Box 69)
    - U.S.S.R., 1982 (Box 69)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 69)